cfsd16.org 2015-03-22

# 1

            CATALINA FOOTHILLS UNIFIED SCHOOL DISTRICT #16
                                     PRIVACY POLICY
We think it is important for you to know how we handle information communicated via
the Internet. This Privacy Policy (“Privacy Policy”) outlines our practices and our
sensitivity to each visitor’s right to privacy.
This Privacy Policy covers the use of the website www.cfsd16.org and the services
provided on it by Catalina Foothills Unified School District #16 (“CFSD,” “we,” “our,”
or “us”). Collectively, the website and the services provided on it are referred to herein
as the “Site” unless otherwise indicated.
This Privacy Policy describes the way information, including personal information, is
collected and used. This notice applies to all information collected by or submitted to or
on the Site.
The content of this Site is for personal and educational use only.
This Privacy Policy does not apply to the practices of third parties that CFSD does not
own or control, or individuals that CFSD does not employ, manage or supervise. By
visiting this Site you (variously referred to herein as “you,” the “User,” or “your”) accept
and agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy and expressly consent to our collection,
storage and use of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy.
Disclaimer. CFSD makes no representations or warranties regarding the website, its
content or any services made available or accessed through the Site, or that the servers
that make them available are free of viruses or other harmful components.
The Information We Collect:
Except as provided herein anyone can search the Site for information or services without
providing personal information. Once your child registers or you register as a CFSD
parent or guardian, you have chosen to provide us with personal information and
therefore consent to the storage and transfer of your personal information to our servers.
        Information we may collect:
    •   Email address, physical contact information and (depending on the service used)
        sometimes financial information, such as credit card or bank account numbers;
    •   Other information from your interaction with the Site including computer and
        connection information, statistics on page views, traffic to and from the Site, ad
        data, IP address and standard web log information;
    •   Additional information we ask you to submit to authenticate yourself or if we
        believe you are violating Site policies (for example, we may ask you to answer
        additional questions online to help verify your identity).
                                                1

System-Generated Information. In addition to information actively provided by visitors
to this Site CFSD may record information such as but not limited to the following types
of information each time this Site is used:
             •  Internet address of the computer being used
             •  Web page(s) requested
             •  Network software access
             •  Referring web page
             •  Browser used
             •  Date, time and duration of activity
             •  Password(s) and account(s) accessed
             •  Volume of data transferred if applicable
CFSD uses this information to monitor, preserve and enhance the function and integrity
of the system. Information is collected for analysis and statistical purposes, and may be
used to help diagnose problems with the server and to carry out other administrative
tasks, such as assessing what information is of most interest to visitors, determining
technical design specifications and identifying system performance and/or problem areas.
Monitoring. In cases of suspected violations of CFSD policies, especially unauthorized
access to student accounts, the system administrator may take such measures as are
necessary including authorizing detailed session logging. This may involve capturing
and retaining a complete keystroke log of an entire session.
Marketing:
We do not sell personally identifiable information for marketing purposes. We may
combine your information with information we collect from others and use it to improve
and personalize our services, content and advertising.
How We Use Your Information:
Our primary purpose in collecting personal information is to provide you with a safe,
smooth and efficient experience. You agree that we may use your personal information
to:
    •   Maintain and improve the CFSD website;
    •   Contact a User for customer support;
    •   Resolve disputes and troubleshoot problems;
    •   Protect against fraud and illegal activity;
    •   Customize, measure and improve the Site, content and advertising;
    •   Enforce CFSD’s policies and this Privacy Policy.
Cookies:
                                               2

Cookies are short pieces of information used by web browsers to remember information
provided by the user, such as passwords and preferences from past visits. Additional
information on cookies is available at the Cookie Central Website
www.cookiecentral.com. Some web-based services require cookies for access. Any
information that CFSD may store in cookies is used exclusively for internal purposes
only.
[The CFSD website does not use cookies to track user information.]
Please be aware when in contact with third parties: you may inadvertently download
cookies we do not control.
CFSD’s Disclosure of Your Information:
To the extent permitted by applicable laws and regulations CFSD, if required to respond
to a legal inquiry, or in its good faith belief that disclosure is necessary, in its sole
discretion may release your personal information. CFSD in its sole discretion may
disclose personal information to respond to legal requirements, enforce our policies, and
respond to reasonable claims to protect anyone's rights, property, or safety. CFSD also
reserves the right in its sole discretion to disclose collected information to investigate or
defend itself against third party claims or allegations. Such information will be disclosed
in accordance with applicable laws and regulations.
To the extent permitted by applicable laws and regulations CFSD, in its sole discretion,
may share your personal information with:
    •   Service providers under contract who help with our operations, such as fraud
        investigators and Information Technology providers;
    •   Law enforcement or other governmental officials, in response to a verified request
        relating to a criminal investigation or alleged illegal activity or to report suspected
        illegal activity. In such events, we may disclose information relevant to the
        investigation or report, such as name, city, state, zip code, telephone number,
        email address, User ID history, IP address, fraud complaints, and CFSD use
        history;
    •   CFSD’s legal counsel in the event of an investigation or to defend against User
        claims or third party claims or allegations.
Without limiting the above, we will not otherwise disclose your personal information to
law enforcement, other government officials, or other third parties without a subpoena,
court order or other legal procedure, except when we believe in good faith that the
disclosure of information is necessary to prevent imminent physical harm, damage to
property, violations of rights, or to report suspected illegal activity.
Security. Although every effort is made to secure network communications, CFSD
cannot insure the privacy of on-line communications. Individuals using on-line services
should also take steps to protect personal information, such as logging off PIV and
                                                 3

closing the web browser when finished using the Site. Failure to do so may result in
personal information being viewed by someone else.
Using Information from CFSD; PIV:
PIV. CFSD is pleased to offer you student information via a web-based version of each
student’s grades/records called Parent Internet Viewer (“PIV”).
Security and Confidentiality. CFSD affords the same degree of confidentiality to student
information stored on PIV as is given to student records stored by CFSD in any other
medium. We are committed to protecting the confidentiality of student information.
Firewalls, passwords, encryption, and audit trails are further used to safeguard each
student’s information. We identify the records released and note the time and date of
electronic access to them each time the student, parent, or guardian accesses PIV. We
have taken steps to make all information received from on-line visitors as secure as
possible against unauthorized access and use.
SSL. All personal information submitted to or gathered by the Site through on-line forms
is handled through a secure server using SSL (Secure Socket Layer) technology. This
information is encrypted while it is transferred over the Internet.
Our SSL web server uses authentication. For other then general information viewing,
PIV must be accessed with an SSL-compatible browser or terminal.
You can tell when you are secure by looking at the location (URL) field. If the URL
begins with https:// (instead of http://), the document comes from a secure server. This
means each student’s data cannot be read or deciphered by unauthorized individuals.
Passwords. User names and passwords provide two layers of authentication and are
stored in an encrypted database that is isolated from the Internet. As a PIV user, your
role in maintaining the security of the student’s information is: 1) keeping your login ID
and password confidential; and 2) keeping the information you view and/or download
confidential.
Confidentiality. All information on PIV is strictly confidential. Its disclosure to
unauthorized individuals is prohibited. If you receive a student’s information or someone
else’s email in error immediately destroy it and notify CFSD by reply email at
webmaster@cfsd16.org or by telephone number at (520) 209-7500.
PIV Account Protection:
Your password is the key to your child’s student records. Do not disclose your CFSD
password to anyone. If you share your password or your personal information with
others, remember that you alone are responsible for all actions taken in the name of the
student account. If you lose control of your password, you may lose substantial control
over your personal information and/or the student’s personal information, and you may
                                                4

be subject to legally binding actions taken on your behalf. Therefore, if your password
has been compromised for any reason, you should immediately notify CFSD to
obtain a new password.
Downloading. Except as provided herein you may read and download information at this
Site without identifying yourself or providing any personal information. However, please
be aware that you may have to identify yourself and/or provide personal information by
logging on to the PIV. Any personal information that you provide to us through email
messages, surveys, or forms will only be used to respond properly to your request.
Except as required by law and described herein, CFSD does not share, disclose, or sell
email addresses or phone numbers to other organizations.
Response to electronic communication. CFSD will make its best effort to provide a
timely response to electronic inquiries. In some cases, the teachers and/or other
personnel responding to an email inquiry or other communication may not be
immediately available to do so. Please allow at least three (3) business days for a
response.
Closed Files:
We do not retain personal information from closed files except to comply with law,
prevent fraud, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, assist with any investigations,
enforce this Privacy Policy, or take other actions otherwise permitted by law.
No Spam, Spyware or Spoofing:
Our users and we do not tolerate spam.
To report CFSD-related spam or spoof emails to CFSD, please forward the email to
webmaster@cfsd16.org. You may not use our communication tools to send spam or
otherwise send content that would violate applicable laws of CFSD policies. We
automatically scan and may manually filter messages to check for spam, viruses, phishing
attacks and other malicious activity or illegal or prohibited content, but we do not
permanently store messages sent through these tools.
Links to other sites:
Website Links. This Site contains links to other Internet websites that are not managed
by CFSD and are not owned or controlled by CFSD. CFSD provides these links for
informational purposes only. CFSD does not endorse and has not verified the accuracy
of the information in or on those websites.
CFSD is not responsible for any privacy policies, content or practices of other websites,
companies or organizations. If you disclose your information to others, you are subject to
the privacy policies of these third parties as and where applicable.
                                               5

Security:
Your information is stored on our servers. We treat data as an asset that must be protected
and use various tools (encryption, passwords, etc.) to protect your personal information
against unauthorized access and disclosure. However, third parties may unlawfully
intercept or access transmissions or private communications, and other users may abuse
or misuse your personal information that they collect from the Site. Therefore, although
we work very hard to protect your privacy, we do not promise, and you should not
expect, that your personal information or private communications will always remain
private.
If you suspect that your personal information has become compromised in any way,
please let us know immediately at webmaster@cfsd16.org.
Third Parties:
Except as otherwise expressly included in this Privacy Policy, this document addresses
only the use and disclosure of information CFSD holds for you and collects from you. If
you disclose your information to others, through the Internet or otherwise, different rules
may apply to their use or disclosure of the information you disclose to them. CFSD does
not control the privacy policies of third parties, and you are subject to the privacy policies
of those third parties where applicable. CFSD is not responsible for the privacy or
security practices of other websites on the Internet, even those linked to or from the Site.
CFSD encourages you to ask questions, investigate carefully and proceed cautiously
before you disclose your personal information to others.
CFSD Privacy Policy Changes:
CFSD may review this Privacy Policy and in its sole discretion make revisions at any
time. We will notify you of any changes by posting our updated Privacy Policy on the
Site.
Your use of the Site constitutes your agreement with this Privacy Policy and any future
revisions.
How to Contact us:
If you have questions about this Privacy Policy you may contact us at:
webmaster@cfsd16.org
Effective date:
This privacy policy is effective April 18, 2012.
                                               6
